A Guide to the Constance Welsh Collection, 1890-1948
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Constance Welsh Collection 1890-1948
Thomas Balch Library
M 085
This collection consists primarily of three scrapbooks maintained by Connie Welsh in 1938-1940. The scrapbooks contain clippings from Loudoun County newspapers about births, deaths, marriages, dances, parties, local interest stories, and property transfers. The first scrapbook was probably created in 1938 and 1939, but contains material from much earlier, such as an invitation to her parents' wedding in 1890 and the published wedding announcement. Inserted material from Scrapbook 2 includes a small photograph of Connie and a cutting of her hair. There is a notebook filled with anecdotes and jokes, some of which are suggestive. Also included is a detailed account of the sale of Susan Welch's personal property in 1946 with the names of those who bought items and the prices they paid.
Constance Welsh
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
James and Cindy Welsh, Purcellville, VA
Alternative Form Available
None
Accruals
2004.0099
Biographical Information
Constance "Connie" Welsh (30 November 1889-12 January 1990) was born to Fayette G. Welsh (1854-1943) and Susan Parthenia Brown Welsh (1865-1948). The family lived on a farm near Hamilton, Virginia, and later moved to Purcellville. Active members of the Society of Friends, the family attended the Goose Creek Meeting. Connie graduated from Lincoln High School; she then attended a business college in Washington, D.C. and worked for the Treasury Department for several years. After working in Washington, she attended Harrisonburg State Teacher's College and the University of Virginia. Connie taught school in Loudoun County for eight years, and then worked as a secretary.
She lived with her parents in Purcellville until her father died in 1943, after which Connie and her mother moved to Leesburg. Her mother died 1948. Connie remained in Leesburg until her own death in 1990. Though she joined the United Methodist Church as an adult, she is buried with her parents in Goose Creek Burial Grounds in Lincoln.
Scope and Content
This collection consists primarily of three scrapbooks maintained by Connie Welsh in 1938-1940. The scrapbooks contain clippings from Loudoun County newspapers about births, deaths, marriages, dances, parties, local interest stories, and property transfers. The first scrapbook was probably created in 1938 and 1939, but contains material from much earlier, such as an invitation to her parents' wedding in 1890 and the published wedding announcement. Inserted material from Scrapbook 2 includes a small photograph of Connie and a cutting of her hair. There is a notebook filled with anecdotes and jokes, some of which are suggestive. Also included is a detailed account of the sale of Susan Welch's personal property in 1946 with the names of those who bought items and the prices they paid.
Arrangement
Chronological
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Constance Welsh Collection, 1890-1948 (M 085), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Obituary, Constance Welsh. Loudoun Times-Mirror, 17 January 1990.
Obituary, Fayette G. Welsh. Loudoun Times-Mirror, 25 November 1943.
Obituary, Mrs. Fayette G. Welsh. Loudoun Times-Mirror, 11 November 1948.
Other Finding Aid
None
Related Material
None
Contents List
- (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook 1 (part 1 of 4), 1890-1939
  - Scrapbook 1 (part 2 of 4), 1890-1939
  - Scrapbook 1 (part 3 of 4), 1890-1939
  - Scrapbook 1 (part 4 of 4), 1890-1939
  - Scrapbook 1 (inserted material), 1890-1939
  - Scrapbook 2 (part 1 of 4), 1939
  - Scrapbook 2 (part 2 of 4), 1939
  - Scrapbook 2 (part 3 of 4), 1939
  - Scrapbook 2 (part 4 of 4), 1939
  - Scrapbook 2 (inserted material), 1939
  - Scrapbook 2 (inserted material), 1939
  - Scrapbook 3, 1940
  - Notebook, 1936
  - Account, Public Sale of Property of Susan P. Welsh, 1 May 1946